<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-posts on Brevifolia</title><link>/blog-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog-posts on Brevifolia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 19:15:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Genealogy of Morals</title><link>/blog-posts/geneology-of-morals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 19:15:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog-posts/geneology-of-morals/</guid><description>So all respect to the good spirits that may govern in these historians of morality! But it's certainly a pity that they lack the historical spirit itself, that they've been left in the lurch by all the good spirits of history! Collectively they all think essentially unhistorically, in the traditional manner of philosophers. Of that there is no doubt. The incompetence of their genealogies of morals reveals itself at the very beginning, where the issue is to determine the origin of the idea and of the judgment &amp;ldquo;good.</description></item><item><title>Ne te quaesiveris extra.</title><link>/blog-posts/self-reliance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog-posts/self-reliance/</guid><description>I read the other day some verses written by an eminent painter which were original and not conventional. The soul always hears an admonition in such lines, let the subject be what it may. The sentiment they instill is of more value than any thought they may contain. To believe your own thought, to believe that what is true for you in your private heart is true for all men, — that is genius.</description></item><item><title>Sunflower Sutra</title><link>/blog-posts/sunflower-sutra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 19:17:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog-posts/sunflower-sutra/</guid><description>I walked on the banks of the tincan banana dock and sat down under the huge shade of a Southern Pacific locomotive to look for the sunset over the box house hills and cry.
Jack Kerouac sat beside me on a busted rusty iron pole, companion, we thought the same thoughts of the soul, bleak and blue and sad-eyed, surrounded by the gnarled steel roots of trees of machinery.
The only water on the river mirrored the red sky, sun sank on top of final Frisco peaks, no fish in that stream, no hermit in those mounts, just ourselves rheumy-eyed and hung-over like old bums on the riverbank, tired and wily.</description></item><item><title>An Essay on Walking</title><link>/blog-posts/walking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 20:11:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog-posts/walking/</guid><description>Then it is that I appreciate the beauty and the glory of architecture, which itself never turns in, but forever stands out and erect, keeping watch over the slumberers.
No doubt temperament, and, above all, age, have a good deal to do with it. As a man grows older, his ability to sit still and follow indoor occupations increases. He grows vespertinal in his habits as the evening of life approaches, till at last he comes forth only just before sundown, and gets all the walk that he requires in half an hour.</description></item><item><title>Song of Myself</title><link>/blog-posts/song-of-myself/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 19:17:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog-posts/song-of-myself/</guid><description>I have heard what the talkers were talking, the talk of the
beginning and the end
But I do not talk of the beginning or the end. There was never any more inception than there is now, Nor any more youth or age than there is now, And will never be any more perfection than there is now,
Nor any more heaven or hell than there is now.
Urge and urge and urge, Always the procreant urge of the world.</description></item></channel></rss>